翻译，时间轴，压制：Bolshevik0
When Gravity Falls burst onto the animation scene in 2012,
当怪诞小镇在2012上映的时候
we couldn't get enough of Dipper Pines and his twin sister Mabel.
我们对Dipper Pines和他的双胞胎姐姐Mabel还不甚了解
So I'll get 107 piddle little facts ever be enough for this beloved
所以我们又找出了这个受人欢迎
but all-too-brief animated adventure.
但实在太短的动画的107个事实
It couldn't.
因为以前那个107系列还不够
That's why we've compiled 107 more facts you should know about Gravity Falls.
这就是为什么我们做了这期关于Gravity Falls的不止107个事实
Think you know everything there is to know about
你以为你知道了你该知道的
the Pines twins, Grunkle Stan and the rest of the Gravity Falls universe?
那些关于Pines双胞胎 Stan叔公和其他怪诞小镇世界中的事物了吗
Inconceivable!
让人难以信服
So sit back grab some snacks and get ready to get your learn on.
所以请坐和放宽 准备学习一个
Just a warning some of these facts could be a little spoilery
不过注意一下有些事实内含剧透
so proceed at your own risk.
风险自负
When asks for an alternate title for the show,
被问起这个动画的替代名称时
creator Alex Hirsch answered Big Trouble in Little Oregon.
制作人Alex Hirsch回答说是小俄勒冈的大麻烦
For the test short, Disney commissioned Canada animation studio
在最初的测试短片制作中 迪士尼授权一个加拿大动画工作室
House of Cool Incorporated to complete the animation.
House of Cool公司来制作
The studio used Adobe Flash which gave it a more static and limited feel.
这个公司使用Flash来制作 导致动画画面更为静态 体验也很有限
Reminiscent of hand-drawn animation like DuckTales and The Simpsons.
让人回想起一些手绘动画譬如DuckTales和The Simpsons
According to storyboard artist Matt Braley final animation was created overseas
根据分镜师Matt Braley的说法
at an animation studio in Korea.
动画最终由海外一个韩国的工作室来制作
Hirsch didn't initially intend to voice the characters on the show.
Hirsch一开始并不打算给动画中的角色配音
When it finally came down to casting the characters,
最终需要配音的时候
others including himself felt that he was perfect for the characters of Grunkle Stan and Soos Ramirez
包括他在内 所有人都认为他适合给叔公Stan和Soos Ramirez配音
Hirsch has commented that
Hirsch曾说过
the large number of fans who correctly guessed the existence of Stan's twin brother
许多粉丝准确地猜到了Stan叔公是双胞胎的设定
contributed to the timing of Ford's entrance.
得益于阿福叔公的时空门
Ford's existence was planned from the very beginning of the series
在动画刚开始的时候阿福叔公的设定就存在了
and many clues have been sprinkled throughout the series.
而整个动画中总是能找到一些相关的蛛丝马迹
One example Stan's license having the wrong name as early as Episode two.
一个例子是第2集中出现的Stan叔公证件上的假名
This twin brother device wouldn't have gone over very well with the cast of the show itself
双胞胎往往因为电视中的演员而争吵
who become outraged when a similar unveiling occurs in their favorite show, Duck Detective.
他们有一次甚至因为最爱的节目Duck Detective的相似剧透而生气
Grunkle Stan's actual name is Stanley.
叔公Stan的真名是Stanley.
He stole his brothers StanFord's identity
他盗用了阿福叔公的身份
when StanFord got sucked into the interdimensional portal during a fight.
在阿福叔公因为打斗意外被吸入跨维度传送门之后
While eating snacks one night, Stan Pines accidentally broke his brothers science fair experiment
有天晚上吃零食的Stan不小心破坏了他兄弟阿福的科学仪器
that would guarantee him a fantastic education.
而这个仪器能帮助他上个好学校
This ruined Ford's chances of getting into West Coast Tech.
这导致阿福失去了进入West Coast Tech的机会
Instead he went to a Community College called Backupsmore University.
相反地他最终前去备胎多大学这个社区大学学习
Stan's brother Ford came to Gravity Falls to study anomalies,
Stan的兄弟阿福前去重力泉小镇研究异常现象
claiming he found more anomalies existed in this area than anywhere else in the States.
他声称在这个小镇发现了全美国最多的异常现象
Ford fell into the portal somewhere in the mid to late 80s
阿福叔公掉入了传送门 被传送到了80年代中期到80年代末的某个位置
so he existed in another dimension for about thirty years.
所以他在那个维度生存了大概30多年
Fiddleford McGucket would have been better off had he stayed in his garage in Palo Alto
Fiddleford McGucket如果呆在Palo Alto的车库里也许会更有钱
and kept working on personal computers.
也就是为了制作个人电脑(PC)而工作着
This is a nod to Steve Jobs who invented Apple computers when in you guessed it, a garage in Palo Alto.
这其实是一个致敬乔布斯制造苹果电脑的彩蛋 从Palo Alto的车库这个位置上能猜到
Ford summoned Bill when he hit a roadblock with his research.
当阿福在做研究遇到困难时 他召唤了Bill
Bill tricked him into trusting him as a friend and gave him the knowledge
Bill假装和他做朋友
needed to build the portal, the bridge his nightmare realm with our world.
并告诉他建造传送门的知识 也就是联通他那噩梦世界与我们现实世界的桥梁
Ford's assistant Fiddleford is none other than crazy old man McGucket.
阿福的助手Fiddleford就是疯狂的长者McGucket
When Fiddleford dipped into the portal
当Fiddleford浸入传送门的时候
he saw the kinds of places where Bill Cipher likes to hang out
吐槽:
无良心推荐同人av9750431和av9891630
他看到了 某个Bill Cipher喜欢逛的地方
and his mind was permanently damaged.
而他的大脑就永久损伤了
To try to rid himself with the horrifying visions
为了消除这些可怕的幻象
McGucket started the blind eye society invented the memory erasing gun help himself
McGucket创建了盲目之眼的社团 自己制造了记忆消除枪
and others forget the unwanted memories.
与此同时帮助其他人忘记难忘的事物
And yes, there's a direct correlation between that device and McGucket losing his mind.
没错 这个设备确实导致了McGucket失去了记忆
Want to defend your home from Bill Cipher,
想要保护自己的家不受Bill Cipher的侵害
注:
出自S2E15 那集疯狂玩彩虹小马的梗
you'll need three moon stones, mercury and a lock of unicorn hair.
你需要三块月球的石头 水银和一缕独角兽的毛发
And we haven't seen Bill go inside the mystery shack yet.
我们到现在为止还没看到Bill进入到神秘小屋里面
So it might have actually worked.
这也许真的有用
Ford is played by J.K. Simmons.
阿福叔公的配音是J.K. Simmons
In case you're not aware,
如果你还没察觉到的话
you got a fair amount of attention this year for winning this little thing
只要你今年(2015年)稍微留意一下
called an Academy Award for Best Supporting Actor in Whiplash.
就知道他今年因为电影爆裂鼓手获得了最佳男配角
Good thing Dipper and Mabel aren't looking for a Jazz teacher.
幸亏Dipper和Mabel并没想去找个爵士乐老师
Some characters such as Dipper Mabel and Candy only have four fingers
有些角色譬如Dipper Mabel还有Candy只有四个手指
whereas others like Grunkle Stan, Soos, Grenda and Wendy have five.
但是像Stan叔公 Soos Grenda和Wendy则有五个
Among the new writers of season 2 is Josh Weinstein
第二季的新编剧是Josh Weinstein
who is perhaps most famous for being the showrunner on The Simpsons for the last two classic era seasons.
他给辛普森动画做过最后经典的两季编剧 因而成名
At the age of 15, Hirsch appeared on David Letterman doing bird calls.
15岁的时候 Hrisch曾在David Letterman的节目上表演鸟叫声
On Mabel's good-deeds list, you can see her feats
在Mabel的好事清单上 你可以看到她的功绩有
included sponsoring a clown, taking out the trash and abolishing the electoral college.
赞助一个小丑 扔垃圾 取消总统选举团
注:
出自S2E14
Gravity Falls got political in the episode. The Stanchurian Candidate.
怪诞小镇的这集里面有政治元素The Stanchurian Candidate.
there was the Ameri-freedoms and Eagle kissing
有美式自由和鹰式亲吻
and the one of the campaign cry of Yes We Stan
而一次活动的口号Yes We Stan
注:
应该是2008年选举的<del>Ass</del> Yes we can
is an obvious homage to Obama's iconic 2010 campaign.
显然是致敬了奥巴马2010年选举的口号
Ford implies to use the mind control tie in the 80s to control Ronald Reagan.
阿福暗示他用控制领带在80年代控制了里根总统
注:
这里应该是Stan叔公冒用阿福身份之后犯的罪
Some of Ford's crimes includes snack evasion, pickpocketing, woodpecker baiting, impersonating a dentist,
阿福的一些罪名包括吃霸王餐 偷窃 使用啄木鸟攻击 假冒牙医
general indecency, golf cart theft, Bingo fraud, telling jokes that go on and on and pug trafficking.
猥亵 偷窃高尔夫车 Bingo游戏诈骗 开玩笑 走私哈巴狗
Jason Ritter, the voice of Dipper, played Jeb Bush in a 2008 biopic about George W. Bush.
Dipper的配音Jason Ritter 在布什总统2008年的传记影片中为杰布布什配音
Ritter is often kept in the dark about the show secrets.
Ritter也经常了解到一些动画的秘密
Early on Hirsch realized that Ritter was a bit of a blabbermouth
Hirsch一开始就发现Ritter有点爱说大话
and has since deliberately kept him out of the loop about true happenings at Gravity Falls.
从那以后就完全不告诉他怪诞小镇的剧情走向了
If Mabel's voice sounds familiar to you there could be any number of reasons for that.
可能有各种原因导致你感觉Mabel的声音有些熟悉
Kristen Schaal is also Louise Belcher on Bob's Burgers,
Kristen Schaal也给动画Bob's Burgers中的Louise Belcher配音
Sarah Lynn on BoJack Horseman and Jake Jr. on Adventure Time. To name a few.
还有BoJack Horseman中的Sarah Lynn以及Adventure Time中的Jake Jr.
Kristen Schaal isn't the only borrowed voice from Adventure Time.
Kristen Schaal也不是唯一一个从Adventure Time剧组借来的配音
Niki Yang who voices BMO does the voice for Candy Chiu
给BMO配音的Niki Yang也给Candy Chiu配音
and John DiMaggio who plays Jake does the voice of Manly Dan.
而给Jake配音的John DiMaggio也给Manly Dan配音
Unsurprisingly, Hirsch's been obsessed with codes and conspiracies since he was a child.
意料之中的是 Hirsch小时候痴迷于解谜和阴谋论
He says he recorded TV commercials on Windows 95
他说他曾用Windows 95制作过一段电视广告
and would reverse them the CF he was being subliminally influenced to watch Pokemon by Japanese spies.
将电视广告倒放 就会发现他说他潜意识中受到日本间谍的影响而去看口袋妖怪
Upon Mayor Befufftlefumpter's death, we learned that he was raised by bears
市长Befufftlefumpter死的时候 我们知道他是被熊养大的
and may have started World War one.
而且可能就是他引发的第一次世界大战
You will never ever see an alien on Gravity Falls.
怪诞小镇里你绝不会看到外星人
Even though a UFO has appeared in the series.
尽管动画中曾出现过一个UFO
Hirsch has a distaste for showing actual aliens.
Hirsch讨厌展示实际的外星人
Ironically enough, aliens abound on a show in the Gravity Falls universe.
讽刺的是 怪诞小镇世界里 外星人无处不在
Hirsch recently commented that the series exists in the same universe as Adult Swim's Rick and Morty.
Hirsch最近说怪诞小镇和Adult Swim的Rick and Morty处在同一个宇宙中
注:
出自R&M的S1E10
For the eagle-eyed viewer in the Rick & Morty episode Close Rick-counters of the Rick Kind,
仔细观看的观众已经发现 在R&M Close Rick-counters of the Rick Kind 那集中
a mystery shack mud comes flying out of the portal.
神秘小屋的东西从传送门飞了出来
Can also see a visual of Bill Cipher on computer screen in the couples therapy clinic
同样也可以在couples therapy clinic的电脑屏幕上看到Bill Cipher的图案
注:
出自R&M的S2E07
in the episode Big Trouble in Little Sanchez.
在R&M的Big Trouble in Little Sanchez 那集里
Hirsch and Roiland also giving each other cameos on their respective shows.
Hirsch和R&M的制作者Roiland也在对方的动画中进行了客串
Hirsch plays Toby Matthews on the episode Big Trouble in Little Sanchez
Hirsch给Big Trouble in Little Sanchez 那集中的Toby Matthews配音
and Roiland has a recurring role in Gravity Falls as Blendin Blandin.
而Roiland在怪诞小镇中的常驻角色则是Blendin Blandin
Another phenomena you will never see on Gravity Falls as a wish base story.
另外一件你在怪诞小镇里看不到的东西是 怪诞小镇的主线剧情并不是基于某个目标的
Hirsch dismisses it as A kid's show cliche.
Hirsch认为这是少年漫中的陈词滥调
注:
二手车勇士出自S2E18
If you thought the discount Auto Warriors were an homage to Mad Max, you are absolutely right.
二手车勇士确实是致敬疯狂的麦克斯那部电影
One episode of Gravity Falls takes over a year to produce.
怪诞小镇中的一集要花费一年来制作
6 months for boards, 2 months for animatics, 6 months for animation and 2 months for retakes.
分镜6个月 动态分镜2个月 动画6个月 再制作2个月
And that doesn't even include writing the episodes.
而这还不包括动画编剧的时间
Because Gravity Falls is a script driven show, most of the writing is done by the writers.
因为怪诞小镇是剧本驱动的动画 大多数剧本都由编剧完成
As opposed to the show like Adventure Time which is storyboard driven.
而Adventure Time这样的动画则是分镜驱动的
The writers room has two sides of cards on the wall.
编剧的办公室两侧墙上贴满了卡片
One with potential character conflicts, crisis is life issues etc.
一面贴的是潜在的角色冲突问题和一些关键问题等
And others with potential monsters and magic fare.
另外一面则是潜在的怪兽和魔法问题
The writing process largely involves mixing and matching these two kinds of problems
编剧过程就是把这两者匹配
and figuring out which can phonetically compliment each other.
然后找出最适合的两者
Creating the backgrounds on Gravity Falls is a three-step process.
绘制怪诞小镇的背景需要三个步骤
First a rough sketch is sent in for approval. Then the backgrounds are inked in by hand.
首先是粗糙的草图被送去审核 然后是涂上黑色
Finally they're sent off to the painters so basically everything about the show is really really intricate.
最后它们被送给画师 总之这个动画制作流程很复杂
hey everyone we're taking a quick break from Gravity Falls facts to let you know
that we also have a movies and TV channel now.
It's called Cinematica and this month is Star War's month.
so if you're a big fan of movies and TV or star wars you should totally check it out.
and with that back to the facts.
Despite the numerous references to David Lynch's Twin Peaks throughout the series,
尽管整个动画对David Lynch电视剧双峰的致敬相当多
Hirsch did not actually see Twin Peaks until he had already sold Gravity Falls.
Hirsch在怪诞小镇上映之前都没看过双峰这个电视剧
A much more direct influence on Gravity Falls was the short-lived 90s kids show Eerie Indiana.
对怪诞小镇更直接的影响来自90年代的青少年真人短片Eerie Indiana
Hirsch said that it's Unambiguously a ripoff.
Hirsch说这很显然是一个坑人货
Artist Bridget Bérenger(?) who went to Cal Arts with Hirsch
和Hirsch一起上加州艺术学院的Bridget Bérenger(?)
was asked to do the very first character studies for Gravity Falls.
曾参与了怪诞小镇最初的角色设定
Dipper is based on Alex as a kid and he should also have a hat.
Dipper基于Alex小时候 同时戴着帽子
Mabel wears hideous sweaters and is Alex's foil.
Mabel穿着丑丑的毛衣 同时是Alex的陪衬
Hirsch only note for Wendy was
Hirsch只记得Wendy的一点
Maybe she's tall. I don't know.
我不太清楚 也许她很高
Joe Pitt who also worked on character design for the show,
Joe Pitt也为动画的人设工作
shared another early sketch of Dipper looking especially scrawny and scratchier looking pine.
分享了另一张Dipper的人设 看起来更瘦而且更粗糙像松树一样的人设
注:
出自S1E05
The costume worn by Dipper in The Inconveniencing came from the childhood of one of the writers.
Dipper在The Inconveniencing 那集穿的衣服来自某个编剧的童年经历
Apparently when his parents would leave,
当他父母要离开的时候
his sister would make him wear a lamb costume and prance around.
他姐姐就要求他穿这套小羊衣服并四处舞蹈
Bill Cipher is Hirsch's favorite character.
Bill Cipher是Hirsch最喜爱的角色
Apparently the character was created early on in the development of the show.
很显然 这个角色在动画制作的一开始就定下来了
When Hirsch was thinking about the design for Bill Cipher,
当Hirsch在考虑Bill Cipher的人设的时候
it struck him as hilarious to take the most ominous Illuminati looking symbol
他突然想到一个很荒谬的最不吉利的光照派图案
and slap Mr. Peanut arms and legs on him and throw him into the mix.
并把花生先生的胳膊腿装上去
Stan's first for a and the conman ship with sham total
Stan最初做的骗人电视广告赝品大卖场
and his memorable tagline of It's a total sham
以及令人印象深刻的广告语为您奉献最佳赝品
is an obvious parody of Sham Wow
显然是致敬了Sham Wow
which is not as blatant about its fraud and admittedly did not work by smearing everything with paint.
当然没有像他这样公然骗人并把所有东西用油漆浸染
Gravity Falls is in roadkill country.
重力泉是个碾动物的地方
Hirsch's stated that giving Dipper and Mabel's parents on-screen personas
Hirsch认为让Dipper和Mabel的家长出现在屏幕上
would Rob the show of its entire being.
将会毁掉所有动画中的人物
Robbie Valentine's Band is Robbie V and the tombstones.
Robbie Valentine的乐队是Robbie V本人和墓碑
We've seen some posters of Robbie wearing eye makeup
我们看到某些海报上Robbie化了眼妆
and peeking from a tombstone with the text You're dead which looks promising.
趴在一个写着你死了 的墓碑上看起来能让人信服
注:
出自S2E08
The episode Blendin's Game was originally going to end with
在Blendin's Game 那集中 结尾本来是
Dipper and Mabel using their time wish to bring Soos's son from the future to meet Soos
Dipper和Mabel使用他们的时光之愿让Soos的儿子从未来回来见Soos
and assure him he's going to be an amazing father.
确保他当上了一个不错的父亲
Shmebulock's family has a continuous presence in Gravity Falls
Shmebulock家族在怪诞小镇的世界中持续存在
Shmebulock Senior is studied by Ford when he first arrives in Gravity Falls.
在阿福刚到重力泉小镇的时候 老Shmebulock被阿福研究过
Hirsch only played Dungeons & Dragons once with Pendleton Ward from Adventure Time
Hirsch只和Adventure Time的制作人Pendleton Ward玩过一次龙与地下城
and Pat McHale Over The Garden Wall.
还有花园墙外的Pat McHale
That didn't stop him from having an entire episode based around a game called Dungeons, Dungeons and more Dungeons
这并不能妨碍他制作一集围绕着Dungeons, Dungeons and more Dungeons 这个游戏主题的剧情
Hirsch built a bar in the Disney television offices.
Hirsch在迪士尼电视办公楼里建造了一个吧
He calls the bar Grunkle Stan's bar.
他把这个吧称作是Stan叔公吧
One of the fast-food establishments in Gravity Falls is Yumberjacks
重力泉小镇中有家快餐机构叫Yumberjacks
where Soos can be seen ordering a kid's meal.
可以看见Soos在那里点过儿童餐
The voice of the wizard probabilitor was none other than "Weird Al" Yankovic, a child hero of Hirsch
可能性巫师的配音是Hirsch的童年偶像"Weird Al" Yankovic
which of course prompted Hirsch to ask "Weird Al" to help create this ridiculous one.
促使Hirsch请求"Weird Al"帮他创造这个角色
After all that debate amongst fans it turns out that Stan's tattoo is a burn he incurred
经历了粉丝们无数的争论之后 现在大家终于知道Stan的刺青是一次烫伤
during his fight with Ford immediately before his brother's disappearance.
是他在阿福消失前不久 和阿福打架时受到的烫伤
The supervising producer for Gravity Falls is Rob Renzetti
怪诞小镇的监督是Rob Renzetti
who was also the creator of My Life as a Teenage Robot.
他同样也是My Life as a Teenage Robot的制片人
Candy is fluent in Korean which makes sense
Candy精通韩语
since Nicky yang also voices Lady Rainicorn in Adventure Time, a character that literally only speaks in Korean.
因为她的配音Nicky yang在Adventure Time中配过的角色Lady Rainicorn真的只说韩语
One of the primary directors of season 1,
第一季的主要导演之一
Aaron Springer was also a writer and storyboard artist on SpongeBob SquarePants during its first 10 years.
Aaron Springer同样担任过海绵宝宝动画头十年的分镜师和编剧
And any SpongeBob fan will tell you that those early years were the best years.
任何海绵宝宝粉丝都会告诉你 最初十年的版本是最棒的版本
Soos has admitted that he writes fanfiction about Stan.
Soos说过他写过Stan的同人小说
Hirsch's first love was The Simpsons.
Hirsch最初喜欢的动画是The Simpsons
So here we are doing a second 107 facts installment.
所以在这次107事实第二期中
No other show has a second 107 facts installment.
也没有别的节目叫107事实了
That's right. The Simpsons.
我们会谈到The Simpsons.
In the pilot Grunkle Stan's invitation have Dipper and Mabel choose any item from the gift shop
在试映片中 Stan叔公请Dipper和Mabel选择礼品店中的任何东西
exists solely as a trick for the audience to get to know the characters.
仅仅是为了让观众了解角色的一个方法
注:
出自S1E07
There's a cut extended fight scene from Double Dipper
在Double Dipper 那集中 多余的打斗场面被剪掉
in which different Tyrone fight each other with toilet bowl cleaners and throw magazines at each other.
那个打斗场面包含不同的Dipper克隆体Tyrone用马桶清洁剂和杂志互扔
Dippers mysterious novel series of choices, the Sibling Brothers.
Dippers看的几本神秘小说包含双胞胎兄弟系列
You can see him reading their novel, the Telltale Fable of the Unstable Table before he goes to sleep.
你能看到他在睡前读这本书 不稳的桌子泄漏的寓言
In lieu of the twin ESP, Dipper and Mabel's allergies act up around the same time.
在lieu of the twin ESP(?) Dipper和Mabel同时过敏
The voice actor for Olmec from Legends of the Hidden Temple voices waddles the pig.
Legends of the Hidden Temple的Olmec配音也给waddles配音
*他只给动物配音
Linda Cardellini, the voice of Wendy hasn't only solved mysteries in the cartoon realm.
Wendy的配音Linda Cardellini 并不仅仅出现在动画配音领域
She also played Velma in the live-action Scooby-Doo movie from 2002.
她也在2002年的真人电影史酷比中出演过Velma
Tyler, the cute biker is now mayor of Gravity Falls.
可爱的自行车手Tyler成为了重力泉小镇的镇长
Purely because he's the only one who filled out the paperwork.
仅仅是因为他填好了表单
注:
出自S2E16
Stan's tourist attraction enemies are Granny Sweetkin's Yarnball,
Stan的景点对手是甜心奶奶的毛线球
Upside-Down Town, Log Land, Corn Maze and Mystery Mountain.
倒立小屋 原木乐园 玉米迷宫和神秘山
Mystery Mountain is a parody of the Trees of Mystery
神秘山是致敬了the Trees of Mystery
which is located within Redwoods State Park in California.
它处在加州的Redwoods State Park
Like Mystery Mountain, the Trees of Mystery both a museum and their very own gigantic Paul Bunyan statue.
和神秘山一样 一样也有博物馆和巨大的Paul Bunyan雕像
Magic has to be in every episode.
每集都必须有魔法
After the airing of the second episode,
第二集上映之后
fans reacted very negatively to there being no sense of magic in the episode.
粉丝们不喜欢没有魔法的这集
Early on a production Hirsch was informed of another long midseason hiatus, separating the season into two parts.
Hirsch在制作的一开始就规划了一个很长的季度间隙 把动画分成两季
Because of this foresight,
在这个深谋远虑的推动下
the writers decided to write and treat the two groups of episodes as the row seasons.
编剧们决定把两个季度设计成剧情上连贯的动画
This led to the idea of ending on a cliffhanger with the reveal of Grunkle Stan's brother.
这个思想指导了第一季动画以叔公兄弟身份仍然为谜的悬念结尾
Absolutely no one's surprised Grenda's voice by a man.
意料之中的是 Grenda由男性配音
But that man Carl Faruolo, is also a storyboard artist on shows such as Phineas and Ferb and Sanjay and Craig.
她的配音Carl Faruolo也是动画Phineas and Ferb以及Sanjay and Craig的分镜师
Lazy Susan got her lazy eye during the very first tour Stan gave of the soon vivre mystery Shack.
Lazy Susan的懒眼睛是在她参与叔公的神秘小屋第一次开张的时候获得的
Susan's voice is none other than Jennifer Coolidge.
Susan的配音是Jennifer Coolidge
First character Alex Hirsch ever drew was Super Paper Bag Man.
Alex Hirsch绘制的第一个角色是纸巾盒超人
Hirsch was in the second grade so he still had a ways to go.
Hirsch当时才二年级 所以他仍有很长的路要走
Hirsch's main advice to aspiring writers and showrunners is to Focus on the characters
Hirsch对编剧和其他制作人员的主要建议是专注于角色
and to write what you know from your life experiences.
然后用你的亲身经历编写故事
Temporal landscape of the show is intended to mirror summercamp.
动画开场中的一幕是在暗指夏令营
Childhood is finite, Hirsch says.
童年是有限的 Hirsch说
That's why time moves forward and, unfortunately,
这就是为什么时间滚滚向前
the show can't have seemingly endless Simpsons-like-run.
而这个动画不能像Simpsons那样无限续命下去
When Hirsch pitched the show to Disney,
当Hirsch把这个动画企划交给迪士尼的时候
吐槽:
第一季2012.06.15-2013.04.02
第二季2014.04.01-2016.02.15 第二季的上映跨度快两年了
the thing he said he was the most excited about was the opportunity to make fun of his sister for 20 episodes a year.
他说最有趣的事情是可以用一年20集的方式戏弄他的姐姐
Gravity Falls is the Disney Channel's first animated 22 minutes serialized comedy.
怪诞小镇是迪士尼频道里第一个22分钟长度的搞笑动画番剧
Legally Disney is not allowed to include any references to
法律上来讲迪士尼不允许参照任何
real-life people, products, politics or religions unless granted permission otherwise.
真人实物 政治宗教 除非有授权
An example of this was in the episode Headhunters,
Headhunters 这集就是一个例子
Larry king granted permission for use of his likeness and name.
Larry king授权使用他的名字和喜好
Hirsch admits his sensibilities, Leaned towards straight comedy,
Hirsch承认他的喜好是 倾向于直来直去的喜剧
and says he's used the magic realism and emotional sincerity present in Gravity Falls to round out the content.
说他 在怪诞小镇中使用了魔幻现实和真情实意来驱动剧情发展
注:
出自S2E17 11:05处
Ford has 12 PhDs.
阿福有12个博士学位
Grenda has a boyfriend Marius von Fundshauser.
Grenda有个男朋友Marius von Fundshauser
吐槽:
根据https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Austrian_nobility#Abolition_of_nobility_in_1919
奥地利贵族制度早在1919年就废除了
An Austrian baron she met through the Northwest's.
一个通过Northwest认识的奥地利男爵
注:
Matt Chapman是动画Homestar Runner制片人 也是主角Strong Bad的配音
怪诞小镇107事实第一期有提到过
Marius his voice is provided by Matt Chapman because nothing says dashing baron likes Strong Bad.
Marius配音由Matt Chapman提供 因为没人比Strong Bad更能攻击男爵
Since summerween was built around the concept that the audience itself was going into the Mystery Shack
因为暑圣节的概念就是为了让观众与神秘小屋互动而产生的
and getting locked up by Grunkle Stan,
然后被Stan叔公锁在一起
吐槽:
谁还记得av15793473 P2里C菌解说过的游戏Press X to Not Die里面喷过的M·奈特·沙马兰指导的烂电影 就是他
the original idea for the tag was for the audience to turn out to be M. Night Shyamalan the entire time.
最初的计划是让观众发现这集的标签是M·奈特·沙马兰
but at last M. Night Shyamalan would not let them use a name or likeness.
但是最后M·奈特·沙马兰并没有给予授权使用他的名字或者爱好
注:
出自S2E03
What Pacifica Northwest is arguing with her parents in the episode The Gulf War
当Pacifica Northwest和她家长在The Gulf War 那集中争论的时候
Disney insisted that all characters wear seat belts.
迪士尼坚持所有角色都应该佩戴安全带
Hirsch really to do an episode where Grunkle Stan creates a cult,
Hirsch真的写过一集关于叔公Stan创立邪教的事情
mocks Scientology into the ground.
叫彻底嘲笑科学论派
HIrsch says that Stan is absolutely an L. Ron Hubbard type personality.
HIrsch说过Stan的性格就和L. Ron Hubbard一样
With question by fans about how he deals with censorship and children's cartoons,
粉丝问到儿童向动画如何处理审查问题的时候
he compared the experience to a chimp constantly beating you with a wiffle ball bat.
他说这就像一个黑猩猩拿着威浮球棒拍你一样
Other than a few computer-generated vehicles, Gravity Falls is entirely hand-drawn.
除了几个载具是由电脑建模以外 其他怪诞小镇中的事物都是完全手绘的
Like in The Days of Yore.
就像The Days of Yore那样
What common advice in Gravity Falls is to,
制作怪诞小镇的一条共同意见是
Take relationships that should be fraught with annoyance and put a little love in there.
让人物关系中充满烦恼再加一点爱进去
For example instead of this stereotypical situation at cops being hard on the rookie,
譬如说 不是像一般警察那样不好好对待新手的刻板印象
Hirsch thought it would be funnier
Hirsch认为这样会更有趣
吐槽:
不 剧组只是想凑个官方cp而已（暴论）
if the Sheriff would be overjoyed every time his employee was inept and give him candy.
如果Sheriff每次都会对他手下的笨手笨脚感到高兴同时给他糖吃的话
Famous Gravity Falls fans include R.L. Stein, Bruce Springsteen and Jon Stewart.
怪诞小镇有名的粉丝有R.L. Stein和Bruce Springsteen还有Jon Stewart
The horrifying sweaty one-armed monstrosity is voiced by none other than comedian Louis C.K. .
可怕的多汗单胳膊怪物是由喜剧演员Louis C.K.提供配音
While Stan remains Grunkle, Dipper and Mabel always go the extra mile and refer to Ford as great uncle.
尽管Stan仍被叫做Grunkle 但是Dipper和Mabel还是喜欢把阿福叫Great Uncle
Bill's henchman or maniacs are called
Bill的手下叫
8 ball, Cryptos, Teeth, Keyhole, Hectorgon, Amorphous, Paci-Fire,
八号球 秘闻怪 牙牙 锁眼 吓人几何怪 无形怪 奶嘴
The Being Whose Name Must Never Be Said, otherwise known as Zanthar
这位名字说不得 或者称为Zanthar
and whatever those weird eyeball bats are called.
还有那些奇怪的所谓的眼球蝙蝠
注:
对于制作者而言 当时的最新一集就是S2E18
After the last episode Weirdmageddon Part 1, it doesn't look like Gravity Falls exists anymore.
在最新的一集Weirdmageddon Part 1中 看起来重力泉镇已经不复存在
So the show switched up the opening title sequence.
所以动画改变了OP
The original sequence now collapses upon itself
最初的OP瓦解了
and we get the weirdmageddon edition with Bill and his cronies supplementing the protagonists.
所以我们得到了这个Bill和他那群伙计补充为主角的奇怪末日的版本
If you play the end of the credits in Reverse you'll hear Bill saying, I'm watching you.
如果你把片尾的人员名单那里倒放 你会听见Bill在说 我在看着你
Killing people isn't weird enough for Bill.
Bill认为杀人还不够奇怪
Instead he prefers cruel and unusual punishment
所以他喜欢更加残酷而罕见的惩罚方式
such as switching the orifices in your face or like for turning you into stone.
譬如调换你脸上五官的位置或者把你石化
The scarred of names for weirdmageddon include Oddpocalypse and Bizarremageddon.
奇怪末日更吓人的名字包括古怪大灾变和古怪末日
Weirdmageddon won because of its silly clumsiness.
奇怪末日这个名字最终被采纳是因为它又笨又丑
The visuals of weirdmageddon were,
奇怪末日中出现画面
注:
这里指的应该是S2E18的18分30左右
in Hirsch's words, Everyone's imagination just uploading into this pocket of an episode.
按照Hirsch的说法是 所有人的想象被上传到这短短一集中
Before beginning production of Gravity Falls, Alex was asked by Disney to help develop the show Fish Hooks.
在制作怪诞小镇之前 迪士尼请Alex去帮忙制作了动画Fish Hooks
He even directed the pilot.
他甚至导演了试映片
Hirsch is also known from the get-go that Bill would cause an apocalyptic scenario.
Hirsch同样也是一开始就知道Bill会制造世界末日
Alex Hirsch stated at New York Comic Con that he would be releasing a 288 pages volume of the journals.
Alex Hirsch在纽约漫展上宣布将会发布一个288页的日志
He guaranteed many mysteries about the history of Gravity Falls
他保证许多怪诞小镇历史中的谜团
and even some unsolved mysteries of Bill would indeed be revealed.
甚至一些Bill的未解之谜会被泄漏出来
All right it. Hirsch is always plotted out the beginning, middle and end of the show.
总之 Hirsch总在剧透动画的开始 中段和结尾
For instance they've already solved the origin of the magic in the town.
譬如主角团们终于搞清楚了小镇上魔力的来源
Good luck trying to get any writers to tell you though.
不过要感谢有编剧打算告诉你这件事